

Spruce Grove, Alberta | Website: michael-j-potts.github.io GitHub: https://github.com/michael-j-potts/Portfolio

587 986 8303 | Michael.jeremy.potts@gmail.com

To whom it may concern,

During my time at ANFCA, I worked as the education departments data analyst, providing statistical analysis of 21 different friendship centres across the province of Alberta. This includes extracting data from hundreds of word documents using custom python functions, and analyzing the data to advocate for funding from Alberta Education to help run academic and non-academic programming for kindergarten to grade 12 students. I utilize dashboards, charts and graphs to showcase the data in an easy-to-understand manner.

At Canuck Place Children's Hospice, I collaborated with the medical team to provide statistical analysis and tackle emerging challenges. I presented on Al applications in healthcare and conducted statistical analysis of symptoms in severely ill children, leading projects that identified trends using machine learning techniques. Further to this, I focused on creating dashboards to showcase my statistical analyses.

I hold a Master of Computer Science with a focus on data science, graduating with excellence. My deep learning internship at Sunstella involved utilizing graph neural networks (GNNs) to create machine learning models for analyzing patient health. Beyond my internship, I also excelled at machine learning through my classes in applied machine learning, deep learning for health care and advanced Bayesian modeling.

Before my Master's degree, I gained practical experience as a Registered Cardiac Nurse and data abstractor, honing my skills in data collection and critical thinking. During my time at TLEC innovations, I reviewed technical journals on fuel recapture and catalysts, enhancing my ability to understand complex research.

In my spare time, I have continued to work on my machine learning skills by creating hobby projects (which can be found in my GitHub page). Specifically, I have created a global life expectancy as a function of health care expenditure dashboard. As well, I have created several health care related IOT projects that gather data which can then be analyzed (such as my diabetic foot monitor).

Thank you for considering my application. I look forward to discussing how my background and skills can contribute to your team.

Sincerely,

Michael Potts

# MICHAEL POTTS

Spruce Grove, Alberta | Website: <u>michael-j-potts.github.io</u> GitHub: <u>https://github.com/michael-j-potts/Portfolio</u>

587 986 8303 | Michael.jeremy.potts@gmail.com

Passionate Data Scientist. with 2 years of experience turning complex data into actionable insights. Proficient in Python, R, C++, and SQL, with hands-on experience in machine learning, data analysis, and visualization. I'm excited to bring my skills in Machine Learning to a dynamic team where I can help drive meaningful results through data-driven strategies.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## **DATA ANALYST**

### **ANFCA**

MARCH 2024 - PRESENT

Worked with the education team on a project focused on providing academic supports for Indigenous children and youth. Extracted and transferred data from hundreds of Microsoft Word documents into Excel spreadsheets to facilitate comprehensive statistical analysis using Python. Leveraged data visualization tools such as charts, graphs, and infographics to effectively illustrate findings and make them accessible to diverse audiences.

#### STATISTICIAN AND HEALTH RESEARCHER

#### Canuck Place Children's Hospice

MARCH 2023 - JANUARY 2024

Collaborated with the medical director on palliative care research. Executed machine learning models, geo-analytical mappings, and statistical analysis. Forecasted palliative care needs in BC using predictive analytics.

#### **RESEARCH ASSISTANT**

**TLEC Innovations** 

**JANUARY 2020 - JANUARY 2022** 

Researched and analyzed chemical catalyst structures for exhaust recapture prototype. Contributed to R&D and innovation in emission control technologies. Developed and edited corporate proposals and technical presentations.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **MASTERS OF COMPUTER SCIENCE**

University of Illinois - Urbana Champaign

December 2022

Relevant Coursework:

- Machine Learning, Deep Learning for Healthcare, Bayesian Modeling
- GPA 3.9

# **SKILLS**

- Languages Python, C++, R, SQL
- Data visualization Tableau, Power BI, Seaborn
- Machine Learning Tensorflow, PyTorch, Keras
- OpenCV, Sci-Kit Learn, NLTK, CNN, RNN

- Statistical Analysis, Bayesian Statistics
- Timeseries Forecasting
- SPSS, Git, Excel, AWS, SaS, Docker
- Communication, Collaboration, Critical Thinking